Remi Teeple

https://remi.works Email available upon request. Phone available upon request.

SUMMARY

Seeking a position in: Software & Game Development

Remi Teeple is an intermediate software and game developer with experience as an Information Technologies and Security Analyst. As a practicing developer, Remi has 6 years experience working in both Agile and Waterfall environments. Remi is experienced in designing, documenting, and implementing object orientated programming solutions to new or existing codebases. Remi is eager to learn new technologies and participate in team oriented environments.

Security Clearance: Clearance available upon request.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Proficient In: C++, C#, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SASS / SCSS

Experience In: C, Java, Python, GLSL, HLSL, (Oracle) PL/SQL

Tools: Visual Studio 2017+, UML, Unity Engine, Unreal Engine, Git, SVN, Bash, CLI, SSH, Docker,

Autodesk 3DsMax, Adobe Creative Suite, QT, SQL Navigator

Additional Experience: AGILE & Waterfall development, Application Deployment, Hardware Deployment, Networking, Web Hosting, Network Traffic Monitoring, Server Management, Domain Management, Technical Design & Documentation, Code Review, Team Management, Product Demonstration, UNIX, Windows, Microsoft MFC, SQL Navigator, Codejock Toolkit Pro

CERTIFICATIONS

Unisys Stealth v3.x Implementation and Maintenance Unisys, Inc. November 2016 rapidPHIRE Security Operations Center Analyst (rPSOC) Phirelight November 2016 Accredited Configuration Engineer (ACE7) Palo Alto Networks January 2013

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Canadian Department of National Defense - MCSC HRMS

Full Stack Developer Consultant - Ottawa ON September 2020 to December 2020 (4 months)

- Implementing, designing, and testing features developed for existing proprietary HRMS.
- Translating user requirements & requests into new features and functionality.
- Developing efficient scalable PL/SQL queries in a two-tier broker and agnostic C++ MFC clients.
- Developing C++ client functionality and UX using Microsoft MFC for HRMS backend user interaction.
- Troubleshooting, identifying, and resolving full stack issues quickly and efficiently.
- Using proprietary technologies to effectively integrate tooling into existing software stack.
- Developing and executing test cases to ensure application and database stability.
- Designing and implementing data models to meet client expectations and requirements using PL/SQL via SQL Navigator.

Algonquin College Simulations Lab (ACSL) / Canadian Aviation and Space Museum (CASM)

Lead Programmer - Ottawa ON

May 2019 to Apr 2020 (12 months)

- Used C++, C#, and MS Visual Studio to develop various application prototypes and tools.
- Using a SCRUM framework, led a strong and collaborative VR programming team that met all project goals through effective communication and conflict resolution.
- Designed programs and diagrams that included mathematical equations and sequence of operations to ensure consistent and successfully executed code.
- Leveraged expansive codebases from previous teams to create new tools and maintain cohesion with modern technologies.
- Presented VR technology demonstrations at CASM and Ingenium Science & Tech museum on a regular basis. Coordinated all demo logistics.
- Developed game and tool prototypes with XR technologies (AR, VR) using C# and Unity.
- Translated UML designs into code and confirmed results with the team during the QA process.
- Developed, designed, and produced diagrammatic team plans that simplified technical problems for game systems of significant computational complexity and storage requirements.

Algonquin College - Capstone Project Mechroneer

Lead Programmer - Ottawa ON

September 2019 to March 2020 (7 months)

- Created a collaborative agile environment, leading a programming team to meet project goals through effective communication and conflict resolution.
- Collected user/system requirements, extensively designed and documented the User Interface (UI/UX), cross-platform networking, and core game systems via UML and modules.
- Developed core software and prototypes using C# and Unity (URP) and acted as the resident rendering pipeline specialist.
- Managed, implemented and performed, using created test cases, system/unit testing and verification of all code produced by the team ensuring quality assurance.

Algonquin College - Capstone Project Blast Radius

Lead Programmer - Ottawa ON

January 2019 to June 2019 (6 months)

- Collected and documented user and system requirements.
- Analyzed, designed and documented the software game system using standard UML.
- Programmed, modified, integrated, and tested game software using vector mathematics and all aspects of the network communications including controller devices.
- Using Agile development methodology, developed prototypes using C++ and Unreal.

RHEA Inc. / Phirelight Security Solutions Inc.

Network Security Analyst, IT Generalist, Junior Software Programmer - Ottawa ON January 2014 to December 2018 (60 months)

- Implemented, configured, and maintained infrastructure components such as: Fortigate, Cisco Catalyst Switches, Cisco Routers, and Next-Gen Firewalls.
- Collaborated with senior management, project managers, technical staff, and consultants to deploy rapidPHIRE security product releases on time and on budget.
- Coordinated customer support services to a global clientele.
- Assisted tech support team in troubleshooting complex network and software bug issues to resolution.
- Remediated networking and security issues across a heterogeneous operational environment.
- Supported rapidPHIRE Network security traffic analytics in-house product by assisting in the beta software development of a 2 tiered Client-Server architecture using Oracle PL/SQL procedures and functions using SQL Navigator and C++/MS Visual Studio.
- Supported data migration and integration to Cassandra Big Database architecture for final rapidPHIRE commercial product with C++/MS Visual Studio.
- All rapidPHIRE product development was managed in Agile project development using a SCRUM framework.

— Designed and documented conceptual, logical, and physical data models for use in rapidPHIRE using UML (Unified Modelling Language).

EDUCATION

Advanced Diploma Game Development

Algonquin College, Ottawa ON Graduated 2020 Bachelor Information Technologies Networking

Carleton University, Ottawa ON 2016 to 2017

REFERENCES

Available upon request.